PRANITA GANDHI

Location: Hounslow, Middlesex, London

Tel: 07932476719

Email: pranita gandhi@hotmail.com

Nationality: British

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pranita-gandhi-12345576/

Summary

Former Biochemistry technician at St Mary's University who has achieved 4 high quality journal publications in the Fruttiger laboratory UCL (2009-2012), including nature protocols with 8 years' experience in academia. Highly skilled and developed molecular and cell biology techniques which include; PCR, QPCR, Gene Fishing, Gel Electrophoresis, Nucleic Acid Preparation, DNA and RNA quantification, TLC and Protein Assays developed at UCL and St Mary's University Twickenham. Initiated and self-started bovine tissue culture procurement and introduced ELISA technique for the first time at St Mary's University, Twickenham which allowed Principle Investigators to develop research ideas. Negotiated Discounts with Scientific company sales representatives on high-cost items such as Daytona Randox and laboratory consumables and reagents via oral (Phone) and written communication (Email).

Core Competencies

- ✓ Molecular Biology
- ✓ Cell Biology
- ✓ Initiative to learn new technologies and Techniques
- √ Laboratory Management

Principle Achievements

- ✓ Co-author on four journal papers including one in nature protocols (UCL Institute of Ophthalmology).
- ✓ Achieved two increment points for outstanding data administration work and stretching beyond objectives (UCL Department of Public Health and Epidemiology).
- ✓ Working towards the NEBOSH certificate in Occupational Health and Safety (Self-initiated CPD)

Employment History

September 2016- September 2017: Biochemistry Technician, St Mary's University Twickenham

- ✓ Enhanced training of students in molecular biology and biochemistry techniques, these include; PCR, QPCR, Gel Electrophoresis, DNA Extraction from Saliva samples, Total Phenolic Acid Assay, FC Assay, ELISA Assays, TLC, and Spectrophotometry).
- ✓ Laboratory Management: Secured and negotiated discounts with high end scientific company sales representatives as Randox, Sigma-Aldrich and VWR on laboratory equipment/consumables to make cost savings within set budget.

PRANITA GANDHI

Location: Hounslow, Middlesex, London

Tel: 07932476719

Email: pranita gandhi@hotmail.com

Nationality: British

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pranita-gandhi-12345576/

✓ Delivered Health and Safety Training; Inducting and training staff in laboratory health and safety procedures these include; implementation of risk assessments, biohazard waste disposal, COSHH, CLP Regulations and Health and Safety guidance notes implementation.

August 2013- July 2016: Physics Laboratory Technician, West Thames College Isleworth

- ✓ Delivered; Biology, Chemistry and Physics practicals from Pre-GCSE till HND Level (Aseptic Technique, API Testing, bacterial culturing on Selective and Differential Media and API Testing).
- ✓ Achieved procurement of consumables, reagents and equipment for Pre-GCSE to HND level practical's within set FE budget through successful liaison with sales representatives from various Educational Scientific Companies.
- ✓ Developed standardised documentation of laboratory protocols for ease of interpretation for staff and students.

January 2012- March 2013: GeneActiv Administration Assistant, UCL Department of Public Health and Epidemiology, Whitehall II Study Phase 11, London

- ✓ Enhanced data handling skills: Downloading and converting data from 100 plus accelerometer devices at a time using GeneActiv software and inputting data in MS Excel. Data entry of participant details into MS Access database and formatting devices for clinic.
- ✓ Arranged for repair of GeneActiv devices through liaising with company representatives using MS Outlook, telephone and letter.

February 2009- January 2012: Research Technician, UCL Institute of Ophthalmology, London

- ✓ Developed and became competent in Molecular Cell Biology Techniques to produce data for publication these include; ISH, IHC, Gel Electrophoresis, plasmid preparations, nucleic acid quantification and analysis and Fluorescence microscopy.
- ✓ Trained Staff and Students in Molecular and Cell Biology Techniques; PCR, Gel Electrophoresis and ISH
- ✓ Enhanced Laboratory Management: Implementation of laboratory stock (reagents/consumables) spreadsheets, securing procurement of laboratory equipment and consumables through liaison with scientific sales representatives and implementation of risk assessments.

Qualifications

- ✓ March 2014- June 2014 PTLLS (Preparing to Teach in the Lifelong Sector) Level 4 (Pass)
- ✓ May 2009- Jan 2012, Animal Home Office License holder modules: 1, 2 and 3
- ✓ 2006- 2008, MSc Molecular Medicine (Merit), Brunel University
- ✓ 2002-2005, BSc (Hons) Medical Biology (2:1), Brunel University

PRANITA GANDHI

Location: Hounslow, Middlesex, London

Tel: 07932476719

Email: pranita gandhi@hotmail.com

Nationality: British

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pranita-gandhi-12345576/

Professional Memberships

- ✓ April 2015- Present MRSB (Member of the Royal Society of Biology)
- ✓ September 2017- Present AIOSH (Affiliate Member of Institute of Occupational Health and Safety)

Publications

- 1. Astrocyte-derived vascular endothelial growth factor stabilizes vessels in the developing retinal vasculature, PLoS One. 2010 Jul 29; 5(7).
 - Scott A, Powner MB, Gandhi P, Clarkin C, Gutmann DH, Johnson RS, Ferrara N, Fruttiger M.
- 2. Pathogenesis of arteriovenous malformations in the absence of endoglin, Circ Res. 2010 Apr 30; 106(8):1425-33.
 - Mahmoud M, Allinson KR, Zhai Z, Oakenfull R, Gandhi P, Adams RH, Fruttiger M, Arthur HM.
- 3. Apelin is Required for Non-Neovascular Remodeling in the Retina. Am J Pathol. 2011 Nov McKenzie JA, Fruttiger M, Abraham S, Lange C, Stone J, **Gandhi P**, Wang X, Bainbridge J, Moss SE, J Greenwood
- 4. Visualization of gene expression in whole mouse retina by in situ hybridization. Nat Protoc. 2012 May 10; 7 (6) 1086-96.
 - Powner MB, Vevis K, McKenzie JA, Gandhi P, Jadeja S, Fruttiger M.